{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which is the most popular JavaScript framework?",
      "options": ["Angular", "React", "Svelte", "Vue"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which company invented React?",
      "options": ["Google", "Apple", "Netflix", "Facebook"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the fundamental building block of React apps?",
      "options": ["Components", "Blocks", "Elements", "Effects"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the name of the syntax we use to describe the UI in React components?",
      "options": ["FBJ", "Babel", "JSX", "ES2015"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "How does data flow naturally in React apps?",
      "options": [
        "From parents to children",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "The developers decides"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "How to pass data into a child component?",
      "options": ["State", "Props", "PropTypes", "Parameters"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "When to use derived state?",
      "options": [
        "Whenever the state should not trigger a re-render",
        "Whenever the state can be synchronized with an effect",
        "Whenever the state should be accessible to all components",
        "Whenever the state can be computed from another state variable"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "What triggers a UI re-render in React?",
      "options": [
        "Running an effect",
        "Passing props",
        "Updating state",
        "Adding event listeners to DOM elements"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "When do we directly \"touch\" the DOM in React?",
      "options": [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the UI",
        "When we need to add styles",
        "Almost never"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "In what situation do we use a callback to update state?",
      "options": [
        "When updating the state will be slow",
        "When the updated state is very data-intensive",
        "When the state update should happen faster",
        "When the new state depends on the previous state"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "If we pass a function to useState, when will that function be called?",
      "options": [
        "On each re-render",
        "Each time we update the state",
        "Only on the initial render",
        "The first time we update the state"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which hook to use for an API request on the component's initial render?",
      "options": ["useState", "useEffect", "useRef", "useReducer"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which variables should go into the useEffect dependency array?",
      "options": [
        "Usually none",
        "All our state variables",
        "All state and props referenced in the effect",
        "All variables needed for clean up"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "An effect will always run on the initial render.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "It depends on the dependency array",
        "False",
        "In depends on the code in the effect"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "When will an effect run if it doesn't have a dependency array?",
      "options": [
        "Only when the component mounts",
        "Only when the component unmounts",
        "The first time the component re-renders",
        "Each time the component is re-rendered"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the useReducer hook?",
      "options": [
        "To manage state in a functional component",
        "To manage state in a class component",
        "To manage state in a functional component",
        "To manage state in a class component"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the most popular programming language for web development?",
      "options": ["Python", "JavaScript", "Ruby", "Java"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the purpose of the 'git' version control system?",
      "options": [
        "Managing databases",
        "Managing code versions",
        "Running web servers",
        "Creating user interfaces"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming language is often used for data analysis and machine learning?",
      "options": ["Java", "C++", "Python", "Swift"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the primary function of a 'for' loop in programming?",
      "options": [
        "Defining classes",
        "Handling exceptions",
        "Iterating over a sequence of values",
        "Executing asynchronous code"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the purpose of the 'npm' package manager in JavaScript development?",
      "options": [
        "Running web servers",
        "Managing code versions",
        "Creating user interfaces",
        "Managing dependencies"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of database is best suited for handling complex relationships between data?",
      "options": [
        "Relational database",
        "NoSQL database",
        "Graph database",
        "Key-value store"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the purpose of the 'webpack' module bundler in web development?",
      "options": [
        "Managing code versions",
        "Creating user interfaces",
        "Optimizing website performance",
        "Handling database migrations"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming language is often used for building mobile applications?",
      "options": ["Python", "JavaScript", "Swift", "Ruby"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the primary function of the 'useState' hook in React?",
      "options": [
        "Making API requests",
        "Managing component state",
        "Handling user input",
        "Rendering elements"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the purpose of the 'docker' platform in software development?",
      "options": [
        "Managing code versions",
        "Creating user interfaces",
        "Building and deploying applications",
        "Running unit tests"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    }
  ]
}
